hey Christian thanks so much for being
on the podcast today I'm really excited
to be here yeah it's been been a long
time coming yeah I think so I think
we've all talked in some capacity over
the years so it's it's nice to formalize
it I learned from the notes that I was
the one that suggested or I talked to
you about getting Apollo on
subscriptions and I'm like vaguely
remembering that conversation there
might have been a Twitter DM or
something I think it was like an email
back when emails were a big thing yeah
yeah I think you were like there's the
subscription thing that's coming out um
I don't know if you heard of it and I
think back then I was still kind of like
chicken [ __ ] where everyone was kind of
getting roasted for it and I was like I
I don't know what this guy's talking
about but you were ahead of your time
vaguely remember vaguely remember it's
pretty cool pretty Co well we can get
more into that in a bit I did just want
to kick things off talking about how you
got into Indie development like you
actually I went to your LinkedIn page
before this podcast to be like looking
for your to write your bio and stuff no
and it's like the perfect kind of like
LinkedIn page it was like you read Apple
for a little bit and then like you just
didn't update it ever again like the
perfect indie LinkedIn like I don't even
care I don't know if I've ever logged in
since then yeah I get a DM once in a
while that they're like I sent you a
message on LinkedIn and I'm like uh
well well our our one mutual Christian I
think is the same Apple recruiter that
must have recruited us oh was it Mike no
this guy Joshua oh maybe that sounds
familiar okay okay fair enough it wasn't
that far off that I was there I was
there a few years before you but so you
were at Apple and what happened after
that cuz the trail goes dark yeah yeah I
like to be mysterious I was there for a
summer internship during University and
pretty much after that I kind of got
that fire in your belly that you often
do when you work somewhere really cool
and I was like okay I want to build
something and Reddit was really big at
the time still is obviously but it was
like really really big especially like
where I was in university and there was
Alien Blue but there wasn't really any
like really iOS first app that really I
loved so I was like you know screw it
this is this could be a fun project to
kind of get my beak wet with so I
started playing with that and it came
along really nicely and I ended up
posting it in like the Apple subreddit I
think and it really took off in a big
way and people were really interested in
beta testing it so kind of got to that
point where I was like oh like this
might have some legs I'm graduating in a
few months like should I go get the big
boy job go back to Apple or something or
kind of see if this has legs and and try
it out for a bit and I ended up trying
it out for a bit burning through all the
savings I got at Apple and ended up
working out pretty well so it kind of
accidental in a way but also just kind
of happened organically I suppose had
you built apps or anything else before
Apollo yeah I had like um an app called
syllable that was like kind of like a
speed reading app it helped you like one
of those ones that like flashed a word
at a time and TR how to help you learn
to read a little faster and it was great
because it made like a few hundred bucks
um over the course of like a year during
University which like you know as a
university student is incredible yeah
yeah like that's amazing and I think
that really like that was back when they
was like oh there's an app for that
commercials were everywhere so there was
this big apps were such a like novel New
Concept so like like I was still like it
it was so hyped to be working on
something like that so it and you could
there were a few enough apps at the time
still you could like push an app and
like get a reasonable amount of traffic
just from being on the App Store oh yeah
Tech crunch would be like there's a new
app out today like check this thing
out which you don't see a lot of anymore
what year was that probably like 2012
2013 I want to say something like that
and then when did you start work on
Apollo so I finished Apple in 2014 so I
think it would have been yeah like the
fall of 2014 is when I started working
on it yeah yeah so it's it's yeah wow
coming up 10 years so what were the like
Frameworks and process you used to build
Apollo yeah that not
so especially like it got a little
better as time went on maybe but like
especially at the beginning like it was
like I was a kid at the University so I
like I guess a lot of developers have
like you know years in the trenches
working at like a big startup or a
formalized tech company where they
developed these like really great
practices and I really had none of that
like my school was very like computer
science theory based so like apps
weren't even taught so it was kind of a
lot of feeling around in the dark and
yeah Apollo I was just working on here
and there like all the time I had and
just kind of putting it together and and
I remember like it took like I posted it
I want to say like the January after
that fall and it was like maybe a year
and a half or two years later that I
actually like fully released it so it
took a long time of just kind of like
fuddling around and feeling in the dark
to even get there and there was a lot of
like from the beta testers there was a
lot of like can you just freaking
release this thing like it's it's your I
think I fell into every like developer
um Trope where there was like feature
creep there was working on like too many
features instead of bugs and yeah and it
by some luck Stroke of Luck it came
together and and released I mean you
kept building you wrote something you're
writing code yeah yeah I was it it just
wasn't very structured like it was like
I need to get to California from New
York and I know like it's West um and
that that was that was pretty much like
as fire organized as I was so your
subreddit has always been very active so
like is that where you would get most
like customer feedback and stuff like
that for sure yeah it kind of made it
easy because you could like the feedback
loop was so close by like it was like
you know you were in the app you can
just poke over here to kind of give some
feedback and that made it really nice
because there was no friction people
always gave really good feedback and
especially during the beta process like
that really helped shape the app for the
better because I kind of had a core idea
what I wanted but the feedback people
gave over the years really shaped it
into something that I think became more
than just like my ideal of what a Reddit
client was it kind of got shaped into
this what the perfect thing for a
community would be and like a lot of
voices kind of shaped it like a
Driftwood going through the ocean where
it kind of gets worn down and in nice
ways but I think that's how all like
most great product well there's very
many different ways to make a product
but I think that is one way right you
have like a lot of feedback and usage
and people and a community that cares
and then I do think you have an aour
like you have an editor somewhere who's
like making some decisions about like
what gets put in and what not that's a
jobs thing right like good products are
made with with friction right he used to
say that like wearing things down and
like working on it until it's that's
very apple right like they would just
grind and grind on stuff no I think this
was uniquely me it was the key the key
man theory of History yeah I think I was
the first when did you like decide or
realize or make like at some point it
became a commercial thing was that
always like I me not that it was like
making money maybe wasn't the number one
thing but at some point you were like
well I have to eat and maybe this like
Reddit client can be how I eat yeah that
was kind of like always like the the
goal on the horizon like apple paid
pretty well even as an intern and I was
living with like six other friends so
like life was pretty cheap and I was
kind of just like slowly chewing through
that but I knew like a microcosm of a
startup like I kind of had like this
fund and I had almost like a burn rate
and I Knew by a certain date I had to
get this out otherwise it would kind of
be Troublesome so I kind of had that in
the Horizon and I knew back then I had
this novel idea of just like you know
$299 one time fee economics were a lot
simpler back then and I and I figured
I'll just put that out and it'll
hopefully take care of itself that was
like the the extent of which I thought
through the monetization but it worked
out pretty well by the end like the the
first day like it got a ton of downloads
because there was a lot of pent up
demand from people who saw the beta but
was full and weren't able to get in so
there were a lot of people who just
jumped on the pro version immediately so
pretty it was like financially viable
from day one of the actual release but
it was a lot of burning through funds in
order to get there yeah I mean it's
financially viable when it's one young
person living you know with six other
five other people right like which is
fine like that's how you should start
you know yeah yeah it definitely helped
a lot yeah it's like the you can do a
lot of things your costs do directly
kind of affect like what you can try and
the risk you can take and stuff like
that and then you can compound later on
right you can build more revenue or
figure it out later but yeah that Sam
alman's talked used to talk about this
more when he wasn't the richest most
famous AI person in the world but like
to just say like your personal burn rate
is probably like your number one can be
your number one hindrance to risk-taking
like as you increase your personal burn
rate it just like lowers the
opportunities that you can take because
you have you know there's lots of
reasons somebody's burn rate it might
not be intentionally chosen that way but
like it is a huge input to the amount of
risk and things you can try and stuff
like this and I think we take I mean not
to say you were lucky but I think we're
all Lucky in some ways like you were
young had the skills had the time had
the like Financial Runway and then you
know of course like had the vision to
build something for a community but like
I think lowering the denominator on this
can makes a big difference oh it it's
brutal because I'll get like Twitter DMS
where people will be like oh like how
should I get into how did get into this
like would you recommend a similar path
and it's like no like the kind of like
you said the stairs aligned people with
like you know three kids and a family
and like you know 10 hours a week of
spare time like that's not a formula I
would have really been able to like
create what I created within so I was
very fortunate I guess to have the
circum yeah it makes it viice not super
transferable right it's not like going
Indie is impossible at that stage it's
just like your Baseline is going to be a
lot higher right and it's going to be
harder it's going to be more challenging
maybe to get off the ground but that is
what's great about the Indie hacker
scene and the ability in software to
have site projects and have a full-time
job and you can build something cool in
just 10 hours a week like you can't
follow the Apollo Playbook to do that
yeah how much how much were you probably
working on that Christian like in that
time uh an ungodly because it's like a
trans it's that like hobby slor barrier
that's like get really dangerous where
you're like oh like I'm working on this
feuture and it's a ton of fun and it's
like 10 p.m. and you were like I think
they call that your life's work I think
is what that's called I guess but it
like you slowly like don't have like
work hours anymore I guess which is
awesome in some ways but in others like
those few hours of night someone might
recharge in some capacity or like still
just plugging away I think there is this
like I won't necessarily accuse the
Indie community of having this myth be
bigger in their world but I think there
is sort of generally a myth that you can
attain like outsized rewards I think
David dhh and 37 signal guys have made
this worse but like to think that you're
going to be able to achieve maybe you
can but like most like great outcomes
came through at least some period of
like intense investment right and it
might not have been that bad right like
it might been something you were
perfectly happy to do but you know you
had again it was like the time of your
life where you didn't have commitments
that you had to do like it was fun right
and you have this intensity where you
build and build and build and build I
feel like there's a movement where
that's like shun that's like bad you
know like oh like you're not being
balanced and like all this stuff and
you're like yeah but like I don't know I
was I wanted
to yeah yeah yeah no no one was holding
a gun to my head and it was like a lot
of fun but it it was just one of the
like you look back at it and you're like
yeah there wasn't inherently like
balance wasn't a word I would use for
that but it was like just in terms of
like trying to replicate that for
someone else like it's it's hard to say
like oh just work on it for you know 80
hours a week like that's all you got to
do and they're like
okay I mean it might be I will posit
that that might be you know maybe it's
not the only thing that matters and
again like I haven't worked 80 hours a
week on Revenue cap probably since the
first year you know maybe there were
spits and spurts of it here and there
but I definitely think when you're in
that like when you're in that nucleation
phase like when you're going from Zer to
one I think I think it's hard to think
it wouldn't be part of the equation
right or at least if it's not necessary
it's certainly correlated right I think
folks that get things off the ground
that was the whole setup and joke of me
kicking this off with like the framework
side of like Christian what Frameworks
did you use what process but I think the
truth is and Jacob said this earlier
it's like different products are built
in different ways and different people
have different temperaments and
different time availability and your
path is a path if you only have 10 hours
a week and you've got three kids you
probably do need to like think more and
plan more and kind of have more of a
process and do some market research and
those kind of things but I think a lot
of great things come out at exactly what
you did even if it is 10 hours a week or
20 hours a week or you get carried away
and do spend 40 hours a week on it for a
few weeks when you're still working 40
hours a week in your day job you're just
passionate about it and you just have to
build that Thing versus like I do think
it can get overly formulaic where you're
just building this thing because you
think it's going to make you money but
you don't even care and that that's a
grind yeah that's I don't think I would
have made it to the end anywhere close
if that was the case because I was using
the [ __ ] out of it so it was like this
was something I mean that's that's super
underrated right being a consumer of
your own product right but that that
process of having people using it
interacting with them and then being the
tip of the spear the person who can
actually build and deploy that's going
to outperform any sort of like framework
or process or like whatever in my in my
experience I think that's interesting I
didn't never I didn't never thought
about it like that yeah that's that's a
just how close the you were to the
consumer the user and then you could
actually just fix their thing like
instantly if you wanted to it's almost a
framework in and of itself yeah I mean
in in absence of framework it's just
gasoline and oxygen or whatever it's
like just put the two and it will kind
of which is kind of like I don't know I
think as I've we were talking about
founder mode it's founder mode week we
recording this for people who are
terminally online but Christian was
asking me about it and I think that's
kind of one of my learnings G uh the
sorry sorry no no please it's a lot of
synergy in this conversation shut up
David I know it's ruined me uh but I
think one of my one of my realizations
over the last few years has been that I
do think that like the core ingredients
being there sort of Trumps all process
or or whatever and that those core
ingredients being like people who can
build stuff people who have a need and
then just energy right just like talking
to them seeing what their problems are
and using very basic reasoning to be
like okay what's next now I say that
with however many years of software
building experience behind me and all
this stuff that I can like synthesize
and like understand what's possible and
what's not and and all of that so it's
it's maybe an
oversimplification but I do think that
like yeah I think there's like a a
desire to over um systematize a lot of
these things which should just be like
organic and and sort of like artistic
such a good word for it like like it's
like you always see those like old guy
billionaires writing the books on like
here's how you do what I did when it's
like I don't know if those steps are
inherently repeatable or it was just
kind of you struck while the iron was
hot yeah or there's even any causation
at all like it's I was doing this and
this is what I was doing when I like
found a gold mine right that
they say it with such conviction like
you read the book and you're like dang I
can do this too and it's like it it
scares me so much when someone asks for
advice to kind of accidentally go down
that path where you're like this worked
for me in this hypers specific case that
like I'll prescribe this to you as
something that'll work in your case too
whereas like I think like you said kind
of having the more organic approach of
like having the right ingredients you
know in The Cauldron I think is is a lot
more helpful than some
inherent uh formula or framework the
tragic part of is is you can have all
the ingredients they still not work
right like it that's that and it
probably most likely won't if you have
enough at bats and if you can keep in
the game long enough and you can keep
trying like eventually you'll have
something I think that will work which
is also I think something that people
are challenged with people a lot of time
cutting their losses you know on a
project that's not going anywhere and
deciding when's enough Christian did you
ever have something where you worked on
and you were just like ah like I think I
need to drop this because like it's just
not worth the squeeze anymore not like I
don't know like bat 100 this guy or bat
in a thousand it's less that and it's
more so like I don't think I start
working on something unless I'm like I
I'm really confident in it being
something I care about which is
interesting not it's not something
you're really confident about working
it's something you're really confident
that you care about right yeah exactly
and to the extent that like if I release
this and I'm the only one who likes it
like in some cases that's good enough
for me whereas like I I almost Envy some
people are kind of just like like they
just got a random idea using the
bathroom and they're like I'm going to
build that this week and like that
sounds like a lot of fun but like to me
I kind of I sit on it a little while and
I'm like where would I take this like
kind of what are what are the what kind
of legs would it have that's kind of
when I invest the time in it and then at
that point I feel like I'm confident
enough and I've put enough time into it
that like not releasing it is just kind
of feels wasteful to me like I get to a
certain extent like cutting your losses
but to me at a certain extent it's like
I thought this had legs at some point I
kind of wanted to see this through to
see if that had any basis in reality and
I haven't had so many at bats that like
I'm sure eventually it's going to be a
terrible formula but like I've only had
like three apps or something and it's
worked out pretty well so far it's funny
use the word care cuz that's exactly
what I was going to say is that even if
it's not a financial success if it's
something you care about it can be
incredibly rewarding and if you're
building it only to be a financial
success maybe you need to and if it has
to be a financial success like you're
burning your life savings to build it
then maybe you do but like I mean even
for me my uh weather up app it's not
been super successful I mean it's made a
couple hundred grand over the last like
5 years
and it's done all right this year but
like it's super fulfilling to me even
though like it's probably never going to
pay the bills or David's the most into
weather apps of anybody I've ever met
like I have one and it came with the
phone and I think it offends him a
little bit that I'm like that's fine
actually that's not true I have some
specialty weather apps but and that's
the thing is that I really don't care
because like we had a storm come through
a couple weeks ago and we had gotten the
beta into this weird state with a data
corruption thing where I could not use
my own app
and then so I went to the App Store and
I downloaded 20 different weather apps
and I did not like them and it was so
incredibly personally fulfilling to be
like I just want my weather app and so
like is it ever going to like make a
million bucks I don't know maybe I'm
going to keep plugging away at it but
like I get an incredible amount of
personal fulfillment in building this
thing and I get to build it with my
cousin which is a lot of fun like so so
in my case you know I work full-time at
Revenue cat it's a side project I don't
even put 10 hours a week into it most
weeks like you know with big updates I
do put more time into it but like it's
pretty cool that I can Tinker on this
thing that I really care about and get
that fulfillment even if it's not making
millions of dollars yeah and I almost
think like if if the financial aspect is
the only thing motivating you like I
don't know how sustainable long term
that is like I feel like you'd burn out
pretty quickly being in YC like I just
name drop that just make sure here but
like uh like why combinator well you
have a lot of people in your bash that
you saw you see a lot of folks come
through and I guess I just r into a lot
of people who are like early probably
like similar to you Christian like you
have Indie hackers like want to get into
it I get a lot of people reaching out
like early stage Venture funded path
like trying looking for advice and stuff
and I can definitely tell the
psychological difference in somebody
who's doing it because it's something
that's like burning inside of them
versus somebody who like wants to do a
startup for like the checkbox and maybe
the money and stuff like that like those
are good too you sniff that out
immediately there's a few tells like if
somebody talks about selling the company
someday like talk about flipping it I'm
like you've already checked out like I
know you're going to try a lot less hard
right there's certain tells they are
minor but yeah I honestly think that if
you could know in somebody's heart and I
think most people don't actually know
themselves right at some level but if
you can know that like I think if it
you'd be the world's most successful
angel investor like if you had a perfect
sense of that I think you would because
it's the it's the people who are like
are doing it for the care of the craft
like the the personal reasons right the
spiritual reasons like whatever those
are I think the folks that will try
harder they'll push harder they'll they
have a little bit of a burning burning
the boats mentality right where they go
like there's no there's no path back
like I'm not turning around right so do
you think you have a good enough batting
average that you'd ever get into that
Angel Investing area no uh no I have
done a little bit I think I'm pretty
underperforming oh fair enough I don't
know we could talk about Venture it's
super interesting cuz I think in Indie
in Indie world the only difference the
only difference between well not the
only there's a lot of like second order
differences that come when you're doing
a venture back company versus like an
indie but really it's just like it's
funding and and a financial thing like
you know we have all the same problems
right you have users you need to get
product Market fit you need to have like
a good culture like within your you know
if it's a company of one it's easier to
maintain that culture right but like but
yeah but I mean your culture just
becomes your personal mental state right
and your personal behaviors right which
matter and so I think I think it's a lot
more similar than people think I just
think the difference and maybe you know
we've been talking about we talked a
little bit before the call about founder
mode which is like this thing that sa
Paul Graham wrote yeah you're a big
proponent I mean I don't know I've never
heard someone so gassed up about it I I
think everybody everybody should just
you know I don't believe in isms as my
friend Ferris berer once said but I I
think everyone should believe in
themselves and so like if it resonates
with you I still I mean I still love
from a movie but like I I think if it
resonates with you you should do it but
I think the process of trusting yourself
believing in what you're building I
think all of these things sort of trump
like how you're funded if you're not
funded like having a purpose to what
you're doing doing stuff that makes
sense to you like as the Builder of a
thing and I think this actually applies
to people not even necessarily founders
of things or like owners of things like
if even your own work I think if we we
we constantly try to like cargo cult
which I don't know if that does that
land on anybody cargo culting yeah oh
yeah yeah yeah I think we constantly try
to cargo cult these like processes from
like other successful companies and
places and it goes back to your point
Christian about like the book from the
billionaire and their retirement years
it's like there's really like you can
copy that but it's probably not the
thing that made that magical I think
this is too for a lot of us in indiand
we copy Steve and I think there's some
things he said and felt and did that
that were core to their success and but
if you copied
yeah Steve Harvey yeah exactly yeah
Family Feud but if if you copied
everything Apple does I think you might
end up with a really broken company
right yeah oh yeah yeah for sure there's
a lot of stuff in there that's not
actually related to their success but
yeah I'm big on big on Founder mode I'm
founder mode number one founder number
one that's me yeah you even changed your
shirt except the yeah yeah I I have it
on right here no it's interesting like
see humans seem to love like I don't
know if it's it's a shortcut or we just
seem to love trying to find our process
to do something better and I don't know
if that's like like an evolutionary
technique or something but like it's
wild how there's almost we love
prescribing like if you do X result y
will occur I think we have this like
desire to map a system of a predictable
system onto like essentially chaotic
data like we're always trying to like
find the underlying physics and
properties and sometimes it works right
and we learn how to swim and jump and
like all these like really complicated
physical properties and things and we've
either learned it like evolutionarily or
or not like why can humans Drive how did
we figure that out right like it's just
like we can map to these insane systems
but then there are some systems which I
just are inherently chaotic and I think
most systems in the world and I think
products and how they interact with
people and whether or not businesses
make money or not I think are pretty
chaotic systems and so we're like
constantly trying to like oh if you just
do okrs and you just do this and you
just do that that's the underlying
physics of the system and you'll be able
to like manipulate and control that
system
and I think essentially they're just
they're always going to be very chaotic
and I almost think that like just
adapting to that chaos kind of organic
going back to organic whatever that
means like yeah that word of just being
like just focus on very basic things
right and you can adapt to the chaos and
not try to like tame it necessarily
maybe is better but yeah we love we love
to try to put complex things into boxes
that don't really map and then we and
then we go like why does nothing make
sense sounds like
chaos is kind of how you built Apollo
it's like you just followed the users
you followed your own Christian trying
to decide if that's an insult or a
compliment no no no no no I'm saying
that's a very romantic way to put what
didn't feel so it felt like a compliment
and I'm sure it's deserved but I
appreciate it so I did want to get back
to kind of like building this business
that started as this kind of crazy
passion project that you hope would make
some money and then you launch it you
launch it and it's you said $299 up
front it might even been 1999 for like
the first week it it it was one of those
things where yeah it was in hindsight
not great because I don't know like the
difference between 199 and 299 or even
maybe 3.99 like it's if you're you
probably debated that a lot or not
actually I'm curious cuz some people sit
and ring their hands over like a price
Choice forever and it's I'm always just
like just pick a price and then you can
change it later it's fine I don't think
I put that much I think like Alien Blue
was like 2299 or something and I was
like that kind of seems like maybe at
the time that was like what seemed
reasonable to charge for a Reddit app
but in hindsight it's one of those
things where I think I did the same
thing with like lifetime pricing once I
finally followed Jacob's advice and had
subscriptions where it was like 1999 for
like the first year which was like
bonker's price when I think it was like
$10 a year for the actual subscription
so it's like it pays for and it was like
I ended up increasing it to like $ 30 or
$40 and like the take rate didn't change
at all and it's like one of those things
we like [ __ ] so you had Surplus
uncaptured like Demand right there 100%
yeah yeah it's it's a lot of chaos but
yeah it was just a lot of chaos over the
years I think where it was it was good
chaos and like the subreddit served
almost as like a continual North Star
like you got two off base it was like
you work on the wrong future for too
long and you start to hear from people
kind of thing yeah they start yelling at
you this is me and Twitter like anytime
where I'm not building what I need to be
building I'll know oh 100% well yeah
yeah and it's great because it serves as
like that North Star so there there was
kind of like um Like a Shepherd of the
chaos in that capacity so it wasn't I
guess as chaotic is working completely
alone like you kind of had like I
likened it to a team almost in some in
some ways but oh like your community
yeah yeah because they managed you in
some ways they always giving feedback um
if they didn't like something they'd be
very vocal about it so it kind of helped
in that way but over the years yeah it
was a lot of just kind of hearing you
know the squeakiest wheel gets the
grease or whatever the're saying is like
whatever they're yelling about that
month is probably something I'll put on
the road map work on that and it was
kind of like rinse repeat for years and
years and years and and it worked out
pretty well we maintain road maps here
but like I think if it were up to me it
would only be the road map would be what
we're working on and then maybe the next
thing like that's it because like so is
that David's thing then yeah whatever he
wants yeah basically oh I fight really
hard internally for things wa we finally
got our uh subscription Auto renew chart
back in Revenue cat after like two years
of me bitching and moaning about it and
it was popular so you know maybe you
should listen to him more actually that
might be a good example of like
something where like you know we have
our like customer interview process and
we kind of trialed some things and
whatever and it was didn't seem it was
that hot and it kind of got back Pro
pring blah blah blah wasn't a tremendous
amount of work but like if somebody's
yelling at us about it like we should
probably just try to build something
pretty quickly because like that'll be
the best way that we learn if it's
really worth it versus like you can put
a lot of pre-work into like oh is this
going to people going to use you should
put a little pre-work in but like I've
Just Seen we maintained like a longer
more complex road map in the past and I
don't know it just always felt
demoralizing it always felt very like it
would do you feel Shackled yeah exactly
like it we would just feel like well I
did want to say this thing I'm just like
at this at some point you're just like
just don't maintain it if it's important
enough it will keep coming up like
customers will keep complaining about it
like we'll keep hearing it and I think
it's been better I think it's been
better it's like we're not fully fully
reactive but like we kind been trying to
push like more reactive yeah there's a
sweet spot there yeah I mean you can't
just like not have any sort of like
sense and you need that like that like
editorial right like you have some sort
of idea of like what a finished Apollo
looks like right or like what the
product as a total looks like well it's
pretty finished now
yeah pretty good
uh but but whatever you're working on
you have like some idea of like where it
might go and you can decide even if
you're getting yelled at by I I say
yelled at in a loving way but like oh
yeah yeah it's an affectionate feedback
from customers you can some things
you'll be like yeah I hear that but like
that's just not the way we're going to
go and you get to make that decision
that's still important oh yeah and I
think think depending on how you
articulate that like there's like I
remember if a customer had like a or
customers even had a relatively popular
idea and it wasn't something I kind of
jived with like I was always afraid of
being like no but like it came to the
point where like the first time I did it
I think I just kind of explained my
reasons why like I didn't think this was
a great idea because maybe they don't
have the full picture and like the
responses were like oh [ __ ] yeah that's
a good point okay and I was like oh [ __ ]
okay I'm not getting yelled at yeah my
move would be to like let me add it to
the road map that doesn't exist that's
trueir don't don't it's on radar that's
what I tell people that's what I tell
people on Twitter when they suggest some
wacky thing it's almost and I'd be
curious if you felt the same way like
they always there's a real problem like
they always have a real issue and then
they would suggest something i' be like
that's the maybe the dumbest solution
I've ever
heard or not that you know I'm being
factious but like that's like not going
to work for like a number of reasons and
sometimes they I find they just don't
have that whole picture like like a
common one for Apollo was like there'd
be these services that like continually
scrape Reddit which is a whole different
story but as a result they kind of have
like cach of every comment so if someone
deleted a really juicy comment you could
theoretically go back and restore it and
that was like a common request like add
that to Apollo I want to see what they
deleted and it was like I see on the
surface why you think that would be
something you'd want but like you get
into all these like safety issues there
like maybe they dox themselves and
people should probably have the right to
delete a comment that they want to
resend and you're kind of getting into
this jelly area of like that's kind of
sketchy and like as soon as you explain
that they be like oh [ __ ] like yeah I
didn't I didn't think about that aspect
of it yeah that could kind of get dicey
and I think sometimes like as the
founder the Creator you have a lot more
you know marbles than everyone else does
yeah there you go Christian's endorsing
founder mode right there yeah yeah I
know I've been I've been trying to get
you guys on
board it's F it's I mean I'm not going
to bring it back to founder mode again
but like I do feel like there's this
tension with like VC back companies and
I don't think W use anybody but I don't
know I think there's well I don't know
part of it I think is like grass's
Greener ISM both ways I think I look
sometimes at Indie folks and go like God
damn you're just by yourself you don't
have like all debt like debt I.E like
Capital you have to return you know you
kind of get just to do what you want so
you have to return that the capital yeah
it's not just I mean we do we should do
a venture capital oneone 101 maybe
episode David but like uh well I mean
they own part of the company right so
like it's not just like free money
yeah okay so so this is actually this is
like a common misconception I think it
goes I think people misconceive this in
both directions One Direction people go
like oh my God the in s don't expect
anything whatever you get the money and
you just build and then whatever and and
and there are I think some Founders who
kind of have that mindset of like
whatever it's stupid money I'll take
their check and then you know I'll just
build whatever I want and like you can't
do that you got to have to have some and
then I think that people have the
opposite perception of like once you've
taken their money like you're owned and
like they you can't you can't do
anything anymore that's also not very
far from the truth right but there is an
expectation that they're going to give
you a dollar and they would very much
like something slightly more than a
dollar back right and like eventually
they expect a lot of their dollars to go
to zero right and they make their money
when not a dollar goes to a120 they make
money when a dollar goes to $10 oh
interesting and that's the misalignment
is like you know they invest in 10
companies five of them go to zero four
of them return $2 and then one of them
returns 10 that's how they make money
they're not like bunting they're
swinging for the fences and they exactly
oh interesting okay exactly and there
comes the mismatch because as a Founder
often a bunt is a pretty good deal for
you as personally right like you get to
build what you want to build you know
you can make a lot of money on that if
that's your motivation and stuff like
that and I'll admit like I don't think I
fully appreciated it when I walked into
it but that's the thing that like before
people like totally cast The Venture
route versus the Indie route you have to
you just have to understand what their
business is if you understand their
business and you're okay with that like
it can be really a good fit right and
this is me justifying now that I'm like
permanently committed to this knowing
what you know now would you have done
anything different you know years and
years ago oh I mean I'm sure there's
like Branch points where I said like oh
no you know of course it's like oh I
could have waited to raise that round
like if I were starting from scratch
would I do Revenue cat like Indie hacker
mode versus not I think the reality is
and this is different depending on what
you're building I think if you're
building an app this is not 100% true
but generally my advice is like do not
raise money if you're building an app
like a subscription app or at least like
bootstrap it to a point where like it's
working and like it's really working or
be ready to shut it down raise very
little money and be ready to shut it
down and expect that it's going to be a
hit or not a hit I think apps getting
Venture returns is very very difficult I
would imagine they're hard to get the
money in the first place too yeah well
and that's why right because the people
have looked at historicals and there
have been winners out there but they're
very rare it's not like in to be SAS
it's like as long as you have a product
Market fit the way that the pricing
works and all of that stuff you can kind
of stumble your way which is been
basically my path it's just stumbling my
way up the revenue scale to answer your
question like going back I think for a
product like Revenue cat like it's so
Broad and there's so much we can build
and I think there's a real advantage
to reaching some level of complexity
very quickly so that we can like service
this industry and kind of become a
leader and all of that stuff that doing
it bootstrapped would have been very
challenging right because you're like
you're constantly hand to mouth you're
like oh I want to build a thing but like
I just all my money is going to pay my
people and like maybe there's a little
bit time I want to build the next thing
but like I got to wait or whatever and
as it stands for us the only real
bandwidth the only real constraint is
like can we hire like can we find people
that will work well with us and can we
scale our team and processes and stuff
and like do we have enough mental
bandwidth to like take that on those are
our constraints cash is not a constraint
you haven't felt that pressure to 10x oh
of course yeah yeah yeah there I mean I
mean you probably have from the from
2017 or whatever yeah I mean plenty of
my investors have hit they're in the
money as it were right and I think
that's also uh you talk about like
decisions like what I do differently
there's some micro choices there where
it's like okay I probably took on too
much money at too high a number that I
wasn't confident enough at the time and
I think that put me under pressure and I
felt sort of like oh god um I'm I not
going to be able to make this and so I
think there's points there where I would
have like this is one of those like non
uh inuitive things where it's like
actually saying your company's worth
less is very good for you right right
set your expectations there's a big
mismatch like people's egos want the
numbers to be as big as possible but
like really them being smaller your
future self will thank you under promise
overd deliver right and so there's some
some decisions decisions there I will
say like I think you can maybe say this
is a benefit or a r or a downside it
depends on sort of how you look at it
but I think it kind of forced me into
being like yeah I've got to build
something massive which I think I could
say I'm happy about because I think it's
working knock on wood like it's like
we're on that path and that's really
cool like I'll be able to look back and
be like geez I built something there's
no way I could have built this like
without taking that path I don't think
right and so that's a pretty definitive
answer then yeah yeah yeah yeah and
hindsight it's like yeah I think like if
I hadn't there might have been a world
where I would have been like oh this is
really hard maybe I should like take off
the gas a little bit we go a little bit
slower and then I don't know where we
would be right like maybe we wouldn't be
in the position we are so and that's a
hard game to play yeah yeah it's it's
it's hard to like go back and there's
really almost no point there I'll say
there was this one conversation with a
family member few years in when we had
like first started seeing some success
and raise some money and stuff where he
was like oh just expecting me to be like
enthusiastically yes he's like oh would
would you do it all again and I'm just
like like uh I don't know I don't think
that's a simple answer right there was a
lot there was a lot of sacrifice I'll
ask you that question like with Apollo
like especially now seeing like how it
all wound up and everything like would
you knowing what you know about the
journey like would You' have done it
would you do it again oh my gosh in a
heartbeat like yeah yeah okay see I made
the wrong choice then in life because I
go like oh man I don't know it was
pretty tough there for a few years well
let's give a little context real quick I
don't know that everybody listening will
know the full context so so Christian
built out Apollo it became very
successful I don't know if you ever kind
of did the Indie hacker like share
numbers thing but you know seems like it
was very successful I think it was the
most liked and Incredibly loved a lot of
very passionate users and then readit
basically shut it down like was going to
charge a ridiculous fee for API access
which was untenable and yeah we don't
need to get into all of that but you had
to like completely pull the plug so yeah
would you do it again it's yeah it's one
of those things where it's like it's
easy to look at it and be like that last
June like there was a lot of strife like
that was probably like Apollo is you
mentioned a lot of sacrifices and a lot
of like you know probably mental
hardships over the years but like for
Apollo it was pretty smooth like I was
how fortunate I was not lost on me it
was very smooth for like the whole time
and I think I kind of got the like the
black hole dying star of strife all at
once and that was rough but it's one of
those things where it's like I don't
know I kind of think of it like a TV
show where if you have a TV show you
really like and it gets like nine
Seasons you're like holy [ __ ] like and
and it actually has like kind of an
exciting ending right right exactly and
so it's TI to be like oh man we only got
nine Seasons like like no that that's
freaking awesome like it was it was a
great run I had a ton of time ton of fun
doing it yeah and it's like yeah I just
feel really fortunate that it was it
lasted as long as it did and and I got
to build something so cool that
influenced so many people and I got to
meet so many different people like you
folks in doing it that it's it's hard to
be grumpy about it it would feel almost
like insincere or lacking gratitude for
you know kind of the cards I was given
yeah yeah was there a part of you I
sometimes I mean this is very joke I
think anybody who works on something for
a long time you're just like God damn I
wish this like I wish I could go do
something else some days right was there
a part of you that was kind of relieved
like okay I got like a good clean out on
this thing I don't do right at clients
my whole life honestly like it's it's a
complex answer because I think when I
was in the trenches with Apollo like
maybe through the chaos I had like zero
burnout just because like if I didn't
want to work on it for a few days and
just wanted to screw off like I had no
employees like I could just do that and
as a result of that freedom Apollo still
felt fresh to me like nine years in and
I was still having a fun ton of fun
doing it so like I guess if you would
asked me when I was still maintaining it
I would have been like no like I can do
this forever like keep it coming but it
was kind of one of those things where
after it ended and I was suddenly able
to do some like freed up some time I was
able to work on some different projects
that I had kind of had in the back of my
head head that I was like oh this kind
of is nice in some ways like I wasn't
like hoping it would end but like when
it did it definitely had some some
positives and and freed some stuff up in
a fun way I mean in not to constantly be
bring it back to venture world but like
because your basis was like your time
and years and whatever and you generally
felt like those were well spent and you
enjoyed it you were clearly in the money
right like the you're and one investor
had return had gotten a great return on
on the investment and like so everybody
you know it's it sucks for people who
use app and maybe whatever but you know
everybody made money as they say oh no
and it sucked for me too like it it was
like in in financial ways and like it's
not how you want to spend your time
right dealing with no no no and I was
having like I'm trying to be
appreciative like it objectively sucked
but like it's one of those things where
it's like you had such a good run that
it's hard to only look at the suck like
you you had such yeah and then there's
there is a question I mean like what's
the long-term ownership I think every
business founder Indie person has to
think about this I think you know if
your inputs are low and and whatever and
it's just you it's like well you can
just shut it down it's fine you know or
maybe you can sell it to somebody that's
fine in some businesses so that gets
more complicated right like as it gets
bigger I think the that's maybe the
revenue cat thing and the Venture back
thing I think probably more generally is
like your outcomes become like just
shutting it down cuz like oh we lost our
main thing and whatever like probably
not an option it's yeah there's probably
a few more yeah probably like okay we
got to figure this out like we got to do
something different and maybe you know
maybe when the better option for the
people would be just to like you know
take your Chips and go home and I don't
think people always make the rational
decision there it's or maybe rational
for the investors but not rational for
the people involved so there's some
amount of blessing in a clean ending and
a and a yeah like the final season
season finale was really intense it was
yeah yeah on Rotten Tomatoes it's like
strong all the way through so like
that's true yeah know I'll take that
I'll take that one of the things I've
always I've been curious about since
last year and you and I have haven't
talked about this maybe you've talked
about this on another podcast or
something but with the subscription
model you could have potentially raised
the price to a point and lowered your
API call like been more stingy with the
API calls to maybe find the right
balance like did you go through that
process in that whatever it was like two
months of kind of back and forth with
Reddit of like can I actually make this
thing work under this new paradigm yeah
for sure like and I talked to like so
many people in the community like giving
numbers and kind of being like how do we
do you see a path forward here and it
was kind of one of those things where
like the the biggest thing that I think
kind of put everything in the [ __ ]
was that they basically gave 30 days
from the day they announced the pricing
to when you would start incurring fees
and in Apollo's case it was in the realm
of like $20 million a year which was
like far beyond anything Apollo was
making it was very much like um like
these costs are going to hit like a
brick very very soon so like what do I
do about that and and there was the
aspect of like I have a certain amount
of existing subscribers that have a
locked in fee that I can't increase
because you you know inherently how
subscriptions work there was a lot of
calculus around that and It ultimately
came down to maybe if there was more
time something I could have maybe like
steered the ship in a different
direction and and made something work
but just the speed at which they forced
everything to happen like I think about
like how when Apple bought dark sky I
think they gave like 18 months before
the API got turned off and I think they
extended like six months beyond that so
it was like having 30 days and it wasn't
only switching out like your weather API
Source it was like switching out like
the API Source it was very aggressive
but like it's one of those things where
even if I was like hibernated Apollo for
like a few months kind of sorted out all
the things and then like resurrected it
with like a new pricing model it's one
of those things where like even playing
that back like the math just didn't make
sense yeah I mean you get this $20 $20
million a year basic expense right like
so like you get okay great you get
everybody to cover that what's left for
Christian like what's left to like
invest it was like I would have these
astronomical costs that by the way like
one of the discussions I was having with
Reddit was like are you able to like we
sign a contract where like these costs
would be fixed at least for a year or
two period just so like say um I make
this work and 6 months down the road you
don't go oh [ __ ] like our clandestin
attempt to kill these apps didn't work
let's double the prices again like so
that wouldn't happen they couldn't
guarantee anything like that so there
was this like the financials just didn't
really make sense where I'd be like
having to charge far beyond what I felt
a Reddit app was worth only to get like
pennies back on the dollar for my work
there and at the same time building on
this like incredibly scraggly Foundation
of it really seems like they don't want
developers on their platform anymore
you're kind of in there in like like a
renter squatting where you're like
you're legally maybe entitled to it but
nobody wants you there and like that
feels like a very shaky Foundation to
build like a long-term product on were
you convinced like that was the the goal
was just to shake off all the clients
like the third party clients yeah 100% I
don't know anything but I'm just curious
why they didn't just say like hey we're
just shutting down all third party
clients because it like is required for
our business do you think they would
just had a bigger Uprising from the
greater Reddit first like I want to say
it was like this big they thought it
threw it a lot but it genuinely did not
seem like that because like one of the
things that was the the weirdest about
it was like this all happened in like
may and like the January I had like an
annual call with Reddit and they were
like no everything's great with the API
we're hoping to make some changes to
like maybe what's available but we're
have like no really big changes to the
API this year that we have like planned
in any capacity and it was like 3 months
later and they're like actually it's
going to be $20 million a year and I was
like whoa that's like a big change from
January sounds like somebody's running
founder mode and that company yeah yeah
yeah exactly um in my head they were
like we can't just say we're shutting
down all the apps because pandemonia
will break out so we're going to have
this kind of like maybe if we just wrap
it up like we're just choking them to
death maybe that will go over better I
hope not if I had to do that for a
business reason and maybe I would maybe
this will probably I'll be tested on
this at some point I'd hope I would just
be like yo this is what we're doing
we're GNA IPO this year we don't want
anybody viewing Reddit not on Reddit so
we're going to be we're going to be this
is why we're doing this so and I
genuinely think myself and everyone else
would have kind of appreciated that a
little bit more because it would have
been more genuine yeah I just like if
you're going to screw somebody just tell
them why you just tell them well one
okay it's not even tell him why just
tell them you're screwed them yeah yes
I'm doing this to screw you great cool
now we know you're at least being
straight forward we can save a lot of
phone calls right right exactly and it
was even like the the stringing along
throughout the phone calls kind of being
like oh no no no we got we have your
best interest in mind like this is all
as well sorry to keep bringing it back
to founder Mo stuff but I do feel like
employees at a company just don't
necessarily feel empowered to say that
right like they might know maybe there
wasn't a directive they might know that
that's the strategy whatever but like
it's just hard to say stuff like that
when you're not you know when the bug
doesn't stop with you you know and then
when you and then when there's an
asymmetry where it's like you're the
whole guy you're the whole thing you can
say and do you can act as Apollo with
unanimity but they can't right so
there's like this real like agency
asymmetry when you're dealing with folks
I don't know if it was that removed
though because like like in normal cases
sure but the the guy I was talking to
was like right low CEO level and was
like the CEO was like cced in a lot of
the emails and was like very privy to
the conversation so it wasn't like I
don't think there was really any
disconnect there like if I had to guess
again this is just guessing but like
from it seemed like there was like
they're iping and there was like kind of
like a quick Rush at the door to kind of
wrap up these Loose Ends yeah there's a
lot going on at a company when you're
getting ready to IPO it's crazy yeah and
they were like okay we've got this loose
end we need to tie it up like who has an
idea and maybe the idea
wasn't uh they can't all be hits no no I
know and you can't fault them for that
and I guess it worked are there any
extent like Reddit third party clients I
think there's like a few but from I
don't hear a lot about them and I don't
think they're necessarily doing well
it's one of those things where and It's
tricky because even if you look at like
the revenue numbers of of a company it's
like when 90% of your revenue is going
toward paying the bills it's like yeah
it's like it's not a great business
right were you like a substantial number
of their daus that they would that it
even made a difference Apollo was the
biggest third party I knew that much but
I imagine their first party was still
bigger oh 100% like probably like order
of Mag that was one of the funniest
things in one of the phone call they
were like do you know what percentage of
our users you are and I was like no like
I I I wouldn't know that and I was like
yeah and I was like no like what
percentage and they were like oh no
we're not sure I was like I have the
numerator I do not have the denominator
right right right and I was like what a
weird question to ask where like
obviously I don't know but seemingly you
don't have that and for all the Venture
back companies out there that are wor
that you'll never get to IPO Reddit got
there they did it through all of it they
figured it out you can do it too you
know just a lot of chaos 20 years or
whatever it was you know it might take
you a few might take you a few but
you'll get there there's hope for all of
us well I did want to talk about some of
your projects post Apollo starting a
farm moving moving I've heard some extra
po about that a lot of wasps because I'm
an AV a user of one of your current
projects which is Juno on the Apple
Vision Pro how has that gone I think a
lot of people I'm curious I think I'm
especially curious why you didn't make
it a subscription after cuz like I don't
know what I paid what the five bucks up
front like in January and it's the
pretty much the only app I use on
Mission
Pro and I and I use it like you know on
at least a weekly basis I would say most
of my ideas don't come from a place of
logic inherently
um it I think it was one of those things
where it was like it was very much like
I think like the week before the Vision
Pro came out YouTube was like eh we're
not going to do it and I was like oh I
have all this like code from Apollo for
handling like YouTube EDS that I could
probably like spin off into an app
really quickly like and again same thing
where I'm like if only like I want to
watch YouTube on the Vision Pro if I'm
the only person that uses this app fine
so I was like oh I'll build it and I was
like oh like and again it was a very
short period of time so I was kind of
like I'll just throw like five bucks on
it that seems like if you paid three
grand for a headset like you can afford
five bucks it wasn't like a grand plan
you're under appreciating your grand
strategy there but you saw that YouTube
wasn't going to take their property like
they weren't going to claim their right
right and you were like ah great there's
a Christian shape hole right here
exactly because it was like they have
this excellent like full documentation
on like this YouTube embedding
capability because like it's so common
that you want to do it in like apps for
instance like Twitter or something where
like someone posts a YouTube video and
you're like how do I play that without
kicking them out to Safari or YouTube
like so they have this like it's
basically just like an i frame where you
can just play the YouTube video there
and I'm like great I use that in Apollo
for years like I'll just play the video
there and and since it's just an ey
frame and they give you some level of
controls I can I can manipulate a little
bit to make it look a little bit more
vision oses and it's been a lot of fun
like it it was it was such a fun Rush
again to be like oh [ __ ] I I've got a
week to build this or like two weeks or
whatever it was and just like what
features are important like what can I
build and I really went back into that
like early Apollo mode of just like
scrambling it out the door and I
remember like we didn't get the Vision
Pro in Canada so I ended up like driving
down to New Hampshire to get it and I
remember like charging at a supercharger
and like seeing on my phone like oh it's
been approved I'm like oh sick okay good
the whole trip wasn't like worth
worthless so it was like it was like
that last minute that it was like
launching the following morning and I
like finally got that approval it was a
lot of fun and it was one of those
things where it's like yeah even if like
the journey was so fun that like I
didn't especially with it being such an
expensive headset I didn't have like oh
my God this is going to be my next
Apollo like this is going to make a ton
of money it was kind of just like I'm
going to enjoy this and hopefully it'll
be beneficial to other people who wanted
to watch YouTube I think the positioning
of the the good media app you know
experience like and in my not only
always be only YouTube right like you
could you could imagine a world and like
where getting that foothold was
definitely worth your two weeks and then
you'll see it probably depends on mostly
how the AP plays out right I'm curious
about that like have sales trickled to
like almost nothing no weirdly like
they've it's obviously like it's very
much like Vision Pro came out High Point
like launched in other countries high
point but it didn't go to zero it still
makes like you know like 100 bucks a day
some days like it's decent for like yeah
it's is a core utility really I mean it
should be built in exactly and that's
the thing and kind of like I'm looking
forward almost the day where like
YouTube does come out with something
because they can do so many things that
I can't as like through the facilities
I'm using it would be cool to see like a
full-fledged app that you can get really
down to the knit and- gritty with do you
have any user analytics or I guess maybe
even just app store to like understand
what the usage of the Vision Pro is it
kind of is like this weird platform for
Apple that's kind of like on the Shelf a
little bit like is it going to like
totally flop is it going to kind of I
mean like I said in my very limited time
I have to use the Vision Pro it's pretty
much all I use on the Vision Pro it's
like I kick back throw the Vision Pro on
watch a little YouTube it's like my wind
down time it's honestly like the vision
like not even my app specifically but
the Vision Pro is a great way to watch
video like it really does excel at that
so it's like I hear you numbers wise I
don't have any like analytics I probably
could check like app store connect I
don't it's really hard because you don't
have you don't know the opt-in rate
really so it's like getting absolute
numbers is really tricky exactly and
it's one of those things where it's like
yeah it's done well enough and people
seem to be downloading it that I it's
never it hasn't really mattered too much
to me like if I had to guess like
personally I haven't like my Vision Pro
usage has declined over the months and
like I don't use it as much as I used to
and it wouldn't surprise me if that's
reflected in the numbers where people
try it enjoy it maybe put it in the
closet and don't but it's cool that for
a lot of people it seems like when they
get the Vision Pro like it's an app they
want to check out yes see you have two
big projects now right that you're
working on yeah that and pixel pales
yeah uh I guess most of your time is
spent on Pixel pil
well or most of your time some paddle
boarding
what oh man I'm terrible at paddle
boarding that's something I need to work
on I'm just trying to pick a
stereotypical like novas scoia activity
I feel like yeah ice skating I think but
no no no I can't do that very well
either I I need a good example but no
like it comes back to me not being the
best at like logic and business is like
pixel Pals does very well and it makes
like an order of magnitude more than
Juno does the the YouTube Vision Pro app
but it's like I was so entranced by like
The Vision Pro um for like 3 or four
months so like I just worked on that a
ton you got nerd sniped is what they
call basically yeah yeah exactly I was
just so entranced by like even though
the numbers were like made zero sense to
focus on that versus the other thing it
it was just a lot of fun to work on so I
ended up doing that for months and
months and months and I'm working on
Pixel Pals a lot more than summer but
yeah I kind of got lost in the sauce a
little there for a few months on what
would be the most beneficial to work on
but it it was a lot of fun at least
pixel pal is is I think it's really
interesting as a project because I think
most Indie devs they us usually stay in
utilities or like whatever and it's it's
kind of at a intersection of games and
utilities maybe right like and games are
freaking lucrative like look the App
Store games are still dominating
actually actually is it maybe it's apps
now are maybe 50% it's maybe equal but
yeah no point and it's a lot like it's
kind of like the Vision Pro where it's
like yeah we stay in the utilities Lane
so long that having something that's
like not at all in that area is kind of
like you're stretching different muscles
yeah well there's just like more
creative surface area like nothing you
don't have to do stuff because people
ask for a purpose right you can just
like build cool things CU they're cute
like and it's fully for the art you know
it's a lot of fun and you get to work
like with Apollo like the extent I'd
work with the designers normally is to
get like custom app icons done but with
pixel Palace like you can get a lot of
like pixel art done by some like really
talented people and you I was going to
ask the next is like are you doing the
creative fully or no I'd love if I was
able to do that because pixel Art's like
I don't know it's so nostalgic like that
would be a really cool art form to get
into um it's one of those things where I
think I would uh Dunning Krueger myself
and be like oh yeah it's just squares
right like I could just draw squares and
then you're like no absolutely cannot do
this no no it's it's like cross
stitching and all that stuff where it's
like it seems simple on the surface but
yeah there's definitely an art to it and
it frees up a lot of time where like I
don't know with like engineering work
you iterate until a point where you like
it's fast enough it works well enough
you know ship it where it's like the few
times I've attempted pixelar like you
shift a pixel right and then left and up
and down and you're like like there's no
definitive like this is done and you can
kind of get lost in the weeds there just
it becomes easier to like let the
professional standle that that might be
a a Hallmark of like good artists is
like they can just know when it's done
you know like just know like it's good
enough you know like I can ship this
I've seen enough things I can ship and
this is on the level but even that I
think peer reviews and stuff like that
is helpful I worked on a iPhone game for
a little while and definitely when you
had a couple artists versus one like it
was a much better process cuz like the
artists could then review and like cross
check critique each other's work which
is true for programming too I think in a
lot of cases have you ever I mean I
mention Apple but have you ever like
worked with other programmers like had
your code critiqued and stuff not since
like University no I don't think so
you're like one of the untouched tribes
like your code is probably just like oh
it's Mayhem there's oh yeah there was
some there were there were some files in
Apollo that were like I'm sure broke
like the Geneva Convention in terms of
like what you what you were allowed to
be doing there's a real freedom to it
though there's a real freedom to it and
I understood it so that's coding founder
mode we're going to keep bringing it
back to founder mode it's like just just
just do what you got to do you could
probably move really fast and it's you
took and you don't care it might not
even be debt it's only debt if it
prevents you from doing something in the
future right otherwise it's just free
money right and a lot of the time it was
like debt in terms of like I think this
is a good way to do it and then like you
know a year or two goes by and you
become a better programmer that's the
worst honestly those are the worst debts
that you take when you don't even
realize it's a debt you're like I'm just
doing this because I think this is like
the right architecture you do a half
decent job and then you realize later
like there's so many things in in
Revenue cat that Miguel and I made
decisions on in
20178 where I'm like why are we still
having this bug and it's like well sir
in 2017 you decided to make this all one
sequel table and I'm like fair enough
yeah yeah get blame yeah no but it's
like when you're not maybe at such a a
big company in some ways it it is kind
of fun to like look back on those things
with like new better eyes and be like oh
my God like that was such a dumb way to
tackle that like I can do that in half
the lines of code with half the bugs
like it's like going back to and playing
soccer against like your Elementary
School team it's like yeah this is easy
like these kids suck like where there's
a certain fun to that sometimes but yeah
it it becomes like anything where if
there's too much of it it kind of bugs
down the whole project yeah but you know
but and you don't necessarily need to
address it I think this is one thing
Miguel and I I think debated and then I
think in in the past I've I've worked in
places where we were much more delicate
with like our architecture and all this
stuff we never wanted to create debt and
I think one of the things we did well at
Reven cat was being like we are going to
consciously create some debt and just
know that like some of it's going to get
thrown away but be judicious with where
we do it and that's been huge we take
debt all the time well you're VC funded
yeah there okay equity and debt David we
need to do a one1 cuz like these are
things like equity and debt totally
different vehicles and they have
different consequences and also people
do take debt it's called Venture debt
and it's super that's actually the
dangerous stuff in some cases but we
we'll do a whole podcast on it I'd
honestly enjoy that next time I'm having
a debate with people on Twitter about it
uh everybody can be informed oh yeah
yeah I'm sure that'll make Twitter
debates much more enjoyable for
you go listen to my podcast aren't
changing the world with our podcasts I'm
saying your tweets change the world and
your podcasts are kind of like a
separate thing yeah you know that's
that's what I'm here for so well
Christian it's been so much fun chatting
about all this and we did kind of wind
around but should we talk about founder
mode one more time I think maybe hit
that little light on
that I think for a lot of folks
hopefully this is going to be a freeing
conversation of like hey I don't have to
have all my [ __ ] together to go build
something just look at this mess look
how successful he
thank you someone finally said
it but like ultimately I think the takea
away from this conversation is like
users are what matter and like creating
value for them and what you did
incredibly well without process because
you were very passionate and founded
community and what people need to do
even if even if they can't you know form
a subreddit of passionate people who are
going to kind of I like what you said
like they kind of managed me you know
your subreddit kind of managed you even
if you don't can't build that kind of
community around your app you need to be
talking to users I mean something we do
a ton at Revenue cat which I deeply
appreciate about kind of our culture is
that you can't let the users Drive the
ship but if you're going to build a ship
that people are going to get on you got
to make sure that like they're going to
find something valuable it's a trip they
want to take I think that's something
you've done incredibly well without all
the fluff and the process and the the
like BS it's like you did it your way
and and you were successful at it and
like I said you're what you know three
for four like three of your apps are
incredibly loved I mean again I'm a Juno
user even though it was like this side
project you just tossed out in a week it
like fulfilled the need and like it's a
genuinely great experience on the Apple
Vision Pro that I wouldn't be having in
the Safari YouTube experience I totally
agree I feel like our industry like one
of the worst like not even like gatekeep
but accidentally gatekeep things I think
we we make it seem like we're like
Wizards over here or something and it's
like people are like oh my God like I
could never do programming or I could
never build build an app that's like
crazy stuff but it's like it's really
not like it's you don't need a lot of
processes you just need a good idea and
like kind of the conviction to want to
see it come to fruition but like you
look at like freaking Colonel Sanders
like you know he just had a good recipe
and he just wanted to make some chicken
and like it works like you you just got
to have a good idea and you want got to
got I want to see it happen but yeah
yeah I just mean it's yeah there's a lot
of processes that I think like from for
people from the outside looks very
intimidating that I think you can break
down a lot of those walls and it's it's
not as bad as it looks all right
anything you want to share as we wrap up
I guess people can follow you on Twitter
you've got a viring YouTube career I
actually freaking loved your YouTube
video on building your own keyboard was
incredible watched the whole thing s it
to my son we're both like a little bit
of keyboard nerds so that was fantastic
that's awesome you're my people yeah I
know it's it's it's like anything it's
just you want to do something and you
put it out in the world and hope people
enjoy it too but yeah I'm Christian
everywhere pretty much I keep the
consistent name so it's it's easy to
easy to find me all right well thanks so
much for joining us this was really fun
conversation oh no the pleasure is on
mine I hope there was something valuable
in there
[Music]
thanks so much for listening if you have
a minute please leave a review in your
favorite podcast player you can also
stop by chat. subclub
[Music]